arizonalottery.com 2018-05-11

# Privacy Policy | Arizona State Lottery

Pursuant to A.R.S. § 41-4152, all State of Arizona agency websites must have a privacy policy. Your rights to privacy are of utmost importance to the State of Arizona in building trust and confidence when conducting business through the Internet. This Arizona Lottery (“Lottery”) privacy policy addresses collection, use, and security of and access to information that may be obtained through the use of this Lottery website (the “Website”). The Lottery will use and disclose information only in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy.

The Lottery offers access to its public information online that you might otherwise request in person or over the phone. Our goal is to provide citizens with a more convenient and efficient means with which to receive information from the Lottery about our games, policies, procedures, and winners. By using this Website or participating in any Lottery game, you agree to comply with the terms and conditions set forth herein and the Website’s Terms of Use. If you choose not to receive your information through the Website, you may also receive information through the Lottery’s informational telephone number 480.829.PICK (7425) or in person at our office in Phoenix (4740 E. University Drive, Phoenix AZ 85034) or in Tucson (2900 E. Broadway Blvd, Suite 190 Tucson AZ 85716).

**1\. Collection and Use of Information**  
The Lottery does not sell any information to third parties and, except as expressly set forth herein, does not disclose information to third parties.

a) Information You Provide: The Lottery does not generally provide through its Website any benefits or services to the public that require entry of personal information online, apart from the occasional and totally optional surveys or interactive contests or games (“Special Events”), which may require that you provide personal information in order to participate.

b) Information Collected from Children: The Lottery does not specifically request information from children and any person younger than the age 21 is not permitted to use the Website under the Website’s Terms of Use. However, the Lottery would comply with the Children's Online Privacy Policy Protection Act of 1998 ("COPPA"), requiring parental consent before we knowingly collected any personal information from an individual younger than the age of 13. The text of COPPA is available at [http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/coppafaqs.shtm](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/coppafaqs.shtm).

c) Browsing the Website: When you browse the Website, read pages, or download information, certain information about your visit may be automatically gathered and stored. This information does not identify you personally and includes the following:

        1. The internet domain (example: aol.com) and the IP address (the number automatically assigned to your computer when surfing the Web) from which you access our portal;
        2. The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;
        3. The date and time you access our site;
        4. The pages you visit;
        5. The address from which you linked to our Website.

This information may be used for security purposes, to analyze trends, administer the Website, improve site performance, gather broad demographic information, and “web beacons” to help us identify when emails sent to your have been received and read. Except for use for security purposes or web beacons, this information will be used only in aggregate form. Such aggregate information may be disclosed to third parties to provide any of the aforementioned activities on behalf of the Lottery, but we do not track or record identifying information from you based on your browsing history.

d) Inquiries. If you submit a request or an inquiry via an online form, email, fax or telephone call, the information collected, such as your name, address, telephone number, or email address, may be used by the Lottery to respond to your inquiry. In the event that you decline to provide such information, you limit our ability to serve you. Still, we invite you to continue to visit the site and take advantage of the wealth of information it offers.

e) Use of Cookies: Cookies are plain text files. They are not compiled so they cannot execute functions or make copies of themselves. Cookies cannot scan or retrieve your personal information. Cookies have a very limited function: to help your browser deliver the full features designed into many of today's websites. These features include smooth login, user recognition, preference settings, navigation, prevention of duplication of survey results, and facilitation of various ongoing Internet interactions.

The Lottery uses cookies solely to maintain personalized services throughout the Website. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you would not be able to sign in or use other interactive features and services that may be offered on the Website.

f) Surveys: From time to time, the Lottery may conduct surveys and will collect general demographic information to better understand and serve our players. Surveys may be conducted through a survey page on this Website or by a third party who has been hired to conduct surveys on the Lottery’s behalf. If a third party is contracted to conduct a survey on the Lottery’s behalf, your contact information will be disclosed to that third party only for the limited purpose of conducting the survey. If we present a survey page on the site, use of temporary cookies is limited to the minimum function necessary to prevent duplication of survey results from that page. A cookie is only transmitted at the time you submit the survey to us. You can always avoid receiving the cookie by not submitting the survey to us. Responses to any such survey or questionnaire may be used for internal business analyses and will be disclosed in aggregate form without disclosing any of your personal information.

g) Investigations and Proceedings: The Lottery may use information that you provide to conduct internal investigations. The Lottery may disclose information to cooperate with an investigation by law enforcement agencies or other governmental authorities and may also disclose information in response to a subpoena, warrant, court order, or other comparable legal processes. Please be aware that in the state of Arizona, laws exist to ensure that state government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by the State. However, if personal information exists on the Website and is requested by a third party, it may be protected under applicable law from release or disclosure.

**2\. Security** **  
** The Lottery and its consultants have taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its computer systems and networks, including, but not limited to, individual authentication, encryption of transmitted data, security monitoring, and auditing. Security methods and measures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day practices of the entire Website.

**3\. Other External Links and General Disclaimers**  
The Website potentially has links to other websites, including third-party sites that are not related to the Lottery. When you link to any third-party website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that site. The Website may also have links to sites that are related to the Lottery, such as a link to Special Event websites provided by the Lottery or by third parties who have contracted with the Lottery to administer such Special Events on the Lottery’s behalf (“Secondary Sites”). When you link to a Secondary Site, you are no longer on this Website, and this privacy statement will not apply to those sites. 

If you choose to link to the Secondary Sites listed above, you may be requested to provide personal identifying information. Such information is not collected, stored, or processed through this Website. Once you leave this Website, you will be subject to the privacy policy of the Secondary Sites. We strongly encourage you to review the privacy policies of the Secondary Sites before providing any personal information.

The Lottery and the State of Arizona, including any agency, officer, employee, or contractor of the State of Arizona, do not warrant the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of any information published by this system, and do not endorse any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be inaccurate or outdated. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.

**4\. Privacy Policy Statement is Subject to Change** **  
** This privacy policy may be updated or revised from time to time, so please check back periodically in order to receive advance notice of any substantive changes to the manner in which the information you disclose on this Website may be collected, used, or disseminated.
